<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to the Octopus&#39; Garden</title>
    <link>https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Welcome to the Octopus&#39; Garden</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/posts/aotw/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/posts/aotw/intro/</guid>
      <description>I listen to music now and then and then some more. Now and then I get stuck into a vicious listening cycle, where I listen to same songs over and over again. In an attempt to increase and diversify my music tastes, I have been listening to a new album every week and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to jot down my feelings here.&#xA;Pop and rock have always been my go-to genres, mostly leaning towards rock.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/posts/blog/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/posts/blog/intro/</guid>
      <description>Hello people. I am InvisibleFoe, a physics major at the Indian Institute of Science Education and Research Kolkata. Currently I am interested in Stochastic thermodynamics and its assosciated stuff. I also like math.&#xA;I made this website because I wanted to learn HuGo. After doing that, the website lay dormant for a year because I was too lazy to even write anything for it.So now in an effort to actually do something about this website, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about posting blogs about random stuff I find cool.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Sabarno Saha, a student at IISER-Kolkata studying anything and everything I like. I like Physics and Maths. When I am not studying, which is often, I like quizzing, watching TV Shows and watching Sebastian Lague or Nerdstalgic on YouTube.&#xA;I like coding sometimes. My computer runs Fedora with Hyprland. I used to use Arch before, but I could not handle a distro that randomly breaks on my laptop when I try to do actual work(which is not often).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
