<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>AoTW on Welcome to the Octopus&#39; Garden</title>
        <link>https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/posts/aotw/</link>
        <description>Recent content in AoTW on Welcome to the Octopus&#39; Garden</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/posts/aotw/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Introduction</title>
            <link>https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/posts/aotw/intro/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/posts/aotw/intro/</guid>
            <description>I listen to music now and then and then some more. Now and then I get stuck into a vicious listening cycle, where I listen to same songs over and over again. In an attempt to increase and diversify my music tastes, I have been listening to a new album every week and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to jot down my feelings here.
Pop and rock have always been my go-to genres, mostly leaning towards rock.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I listen to music now and then and then some more. Now and then I get stuck into a vicious listening cycle, where I listen to same songs over and over again. In an attempt to increase and diversify my music tastes, I have been listening to a new album every week and I&rsquo;ll try to jot down my feelings here.</p>
<p>Pop and rock have always been my go-to genres, mostly leaning towards rock. Recently, I have been exploring hindi rock. Some of my favourite bands playing hindi rock are listed in the <a href="https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/about/">About me</a> section.</p>
<p>A lot of Indian bands playing rock music, tend to have metal undertones, which I do not particularly like. The bands that do make rock music tend to do it quite well. A lot of indian rock bands are quite underappreciated. I plan on writing reviews of albums I listen to during a particular time period, doesn&rsquo;t have to be a week. AoTW(Album of the Week) just sounds a lot catchier than AoaPTP(Album of a particular time period), hence, the name.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
