<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Welcome to the Octopus&#39; Garden</title>
        <link>https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Welcome to the Octopus&#39; Garden</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>The Mobius Strip</title>
            <link>https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/posts/mobius/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/posts/mobius/</guid>
            <description>Introduction Let&amp;rsquo;s begin with a rectangular piece of paper, which is sufficiently long. Take one end of the piece of the paper and rotate it by 180 degrees, and attach it to the other end. What you have just made(if done correctly) is something called a Möbius strip(or Moebius). This is a fun shape that a lot of kids make with some free time and a piece of paper. In this somewhat short article, we will see a formula that describes a Möbius strip in 3D Euclidean Space, and ultimately why that formula is wrong.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>Let&rsquo;s begin with a rectangular piece of paper, which is sufficiently long. Take one end of the piece of the paper and rotate it by 180 degrees, and attach it to the other end.
What you have just made(if done correctly) is something called a Möbius strip(or Moebius). This is a fun shape that a lot of kids make with some free time and a piece of paper.
In this somewhat short article, we will see a formula that describes a Möbius strip in 3D Euclidean Space, and ultimately why that formula is wrong.</p>
<h2 id="the-möbius-strip">The Möbius Strip</h2>
<p>The Möbius(or Moebius) strip is the simplest non orientable surface.(More on this later). In fact, every non orientable surface contains a Moebius strip. If one constructs a Moebisu strip, one can see that it is one sided. A square has two</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Introduction</title>
            <link>https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/posts/test/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://theinvisiblefoe.github.io/posts/test/</guid>
            <description>Hello people. I am InvisibleFoe, a physics major at the Indian Institute of Science Education and Research Kolkata. Currently I am interested in Stochastic thermodynamics and its assosciated stuff. I also like math.
I made this website because I wanted to learn HuGo. After doing that, the website lay dormant for a year because I was too lazy to even write anything for it.So now in an effort to actually do something about this website, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about posting blogs about random stuff I find cool.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello people. I am InvisibleFoe, a physics major at the Indian Institute of Science Education and Research Kolkata. Currently I am interested in Stochastic thermodynamics and its assosciated stuff.
I also like math.</p>
<p>I made this website because I wanted to learn HuGo. After doing that, the website lay dormant for a year because I was too lazy to even write anything for it.So now in an effort to actually do something about this website, I&rsquo;ve been thinking about posting blogs about
random stuff I find cool. Also, I need to improve my writing skills because they are currently abysmal and resembles how a preteen might write their essay for an exam.  I might also write some
album reviews in a different page, but I am lazy. Finally, welcome to the Octopus Garden and it&rsquo;s horrendously written blogs.
This is a list of the stuff I have written till now.(I will hyperlink them later).</p>
<ul>
<li>The Moebius Strip</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
